The final piece of this process is to
流程里的最后一步是
understand our testing and learning plan for the analytics brief.
分析摘要的测试与学习计划
You may feel uncertain you have everything you need to take action on this segment,
你可能会质疑自己是否准备好了 可以做出行动计划了
or you may find that there are still more insights required.
或者是否还有其他洞察尚未发现
For this, we need to ask ourselves three questions.
这时候 我们就需要问自己三个问题
What should we study further?
我们应该深入研究哪些地方？
What analysis and data do we need?
我们需要什么数据和分析？
What should we try? Let's assume for our game day promotion,
我们应该试行什么样的想法？回到超市例子 假如要做一个决赛促销
we know that we need to study what teams are favorite in our neighborhoods.
我们知道需要去研究哪个队在附近的社区里最受欢迎
We have to look at which team makes up the majority of
我们的客户、或者目标客户群体里
our customer or the desired customer segment that we're going after.
喜欢哪个队的群体最大？
We also know that we need to reduce costs as this was part of the original ask,
另外 最开始也提到过 要缩减成本
and so we know that we need to go back and study that more.
所以这一部分也需要我们回过头去深入研究
We still haven't finished all of our analysis here.
这还不算完成了分析
We need to run this again and figure out what cost reductions can come into play.
我们还需要总体过一遍 然后看看哪些成本控制措施可以被试行
Also, we know that we need to study the impact to revenue further.
以及衡量这些措施对营收情况的影响
We have yet to define the actual smart goal for this,
对于这个部分 我们还没有设置一个有效的 SMART 目标
and so we'll make note to do a deeper dive into
所以我们后续需要认真研究有哪些指标
the actual metric by which we think we can improve revenue.
可以帮助我们进一步提高盈利
We may also evaluate that we're going to need data on the best time to run a TV campaign
另外 我们也需要知道投放电视广告的最佳时机是什么时候？
or information on which TV channels
以及将信息投放到哪个频道能
actually serve the customers that we're hoping to capture.
帮助我们触达到目标群体
We may also want to know when those games are running,
还有一些其他相关信息需要了解 包括赛季的时间
the schedule of events,
比赛安排
and we may even decide that we're going to change the teams we
甚至要考虑是否要根据比赛的安排
feature based on the games as they're coming up.
来随时调整我们主打的队伍
Now when it comes to what should we try, well,
那么我们应该做些什么呢？
we know that we wanted to try discounting but we may also
之前提到可以打折
want to try not discounting because we do need to get that revenue up.
但是如果可以 我们也偏向于不打折 毕竟提高利润是我们的目标之一
If we can sell the same amount of product without
如果可以不提供打折
a discount just from our promotional efforts,
营销活动也可以达到同样的效果
well, then we're there.
何乐而不为呢
As you can see, a simple exercise such as
所以 你看到了 分析摘要这样一项简单的练习
the analytic brief can unlock a lot of fantastic insight and help you
可以帮助我们取得很多很好的洞察
pull out of the tools and into the creative storytelling and
从繁琐的工具中抽身而出 转到创新式思维
creative problem-solving that end up going hand in hand with analytics.
同时 想出要解决分析中得出的问题的创新式解决方案